SUMMER BARCLAY

TECHNICAL WRITER & FRONT-END WEB **DEVELOPER**

Email: summer.barclay@gmail.com Website: www.SummerBarclay.com

LinkedIn: summerbarclay

GitHub: Mavyllos

Phone: (480) - 703-5525

Summary

Technical Writer and Front-end Web Developer with experience in content creation, a track record of efficiency, and a lean toward the creative.

Skills

Technical Writing

Experience in technical content creation, including API documentation, using both JSON and XML, online help, user manuals, and many other types of internal and client-facing

Web Development

Focused on front-end web development, including CSS, HTML, and JavaScript, using front-end frameworks such as AngularJS, SASS, Bootstrap, and others.

documentation.

Technical Writing Tools and **Technologies** Author-It Adobe Acrobat Pro FrameMaker Adobe Photoshop Microsoft Word SharePoint

Microsoft PowerPoint

Microsoft Excel

Web **Development** Tools and *Technologies*

| HTML | Alexa Skills Kit |
|------------|------------------|
| CSS | AWS Lambda |
| SASS | Bootstrap |
| JavaScript | Ionic |
| AngularJS | Apache Cordova |
| JQuery | GitHub |
| Express JS | PostgresSQL |
| Node JS | |

SnagIt

Education

Galvanize, Inc - Seattle, WA Certificate of Web Development

July 2017

Links to my Web Development Student projects can be viewed in my portfolio at www.SummerBarclay.com.

Experience

Galvanize, Inc. - Seattle, WA

2017 - Current

Assistant Instructor

Assisted the lead instructor with several evening "Learn to Code" workshops at the Seattle Galvanize campus, including "Intro to Web Development", "Intro to JavaScript", and "Alexa Skill Development Workshop", in partnership with Amazon.

TSYS Acquiring Solutions - Tempe, AZ

2014 - 2016

Technical Communicator

Tasked with writing, editing, and maintaining technical copy for multiple types of documentation, including API file specifications, quick reference guides, fillable forms, product release pages, and many others.

Developed user-friendly educational content and reference materials, working closely with development teams to obtain required information.

Incorporated elements and illustrations into documents to convey technical concepts in easily understood formats.

Developed detailed project scope documentation for each deliverable, including requirements, timelines, expectations and final publication details

Ports America - Chandler, AZ Billing Analyst II

2011 - 2013

Coordinated and executed accounting and administrative functions to support daily operations for major ports in New Orleans, Baton Rouge, and Gulfport.

Addressed all customer complaints regarding billing discrepancies; collaborated with port personnel to research the issue and implement proper resolution.

Created a database for inventory tracking to improve accountability and accuracy of work performed.

Developed, updated, and maintained documentation for training.